Where is the Sun in its lifetime? Is it
halfway through? Is it closer to the
end? Well, if you map out the stars with
the hotter ones toward the left and the
brighter ones [clears throat] toward the
top, you'll get this famous chart
showing a star's [music]
life. Our Sun is currently here, where
stars spend most of their life. When
stars like ours age, they start to run
out of hydrogen fuel, causing the core
to shrink. This compression then creates
heat and pressure that pushes the outer
layer of the stars outward, [music]
growing into a red giant. We think
that'll happen to our Sun in about 5
billion years. It'll get so big, it'll
engulf Mercury and Venus, and maybe even
Earth. Then, in about a billion years
after that, it'll use up all of its fuel
and collapse into a white dwarf, cooling
and dimming over billions more years. We
think the Sun formed 4.6 billion years
ago, so it's about halfway through to
becoming a red giant. But stars that are
much more massive than ours grow into
super giants, and then burst into a
supernova, leaving [music] behind a
neutron star or a black hole. But what
would happen if you dove deeper into the
Sun? To see that, subscribe.